{
	"questions": [
		{
			"category": "PUBLIC_SAFETY",
			"question": "When near a pedestrian crossing, as the pedestrians are waiting to cross the road, what should you do?",
			"options": [
				"Sound horn and proceed",
				"Slow down, sound horn and pass",
				"Stop the vehicle and wait till the pedestrians cross the road and then proceed"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},
		{
			"category": "PUBLIC_SAFETY",
			"question": "A person driving a vehicle in a public place without a licence, is liable for:",
			"options": [
				"Penalty only",
				"Penalty for the driver and the owner and/ or seizure of vehicle",
				"A warning"
			],
			"answer": 2
		},
		{
			"category": "BASIC_UNDERSTANDING",
			"question": "While parking your vehicle on a downward gradient, in addition to the application of hand brake, the gear engaged should be:",
			"options": ["In neutral", "In first", "In reverse"],
			"answer": 3
		},
		{
			"category": "PUBLIC_SAFETY",
			"question": "When a vehicle is involved in an accident causing injury to any person, what should you do?",
			"options": [
				"Take the vehicle to the nearest police station and report the accident",
				"Stop the vehicle and report to the police station",
				"Take all reasonable steps to secure medical attention to the injured and report to the nearest police station within 24 hours"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},
		{
			"category": "ROAD_KNOWLEDGE",
			"question": "On a road designated as one way, which of the following holds true?",
			"options": [
				"Parking is prohibited",
				"Overtaking is prohibited",
				"Should not drive in reverse gear"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},
		{
			"category": "PUBLIC_SAFETY",
			"question": "When a blind person is crossing the road holding a white cane, the driver should:",
			"options": [
				"Consider the white cane as a traffic sign to stop the vehicle",
				"Blow the horn and proceed",
				"Slow down and proceed with caution"
			],
			"answer": 1
		},
		{
			"category": "PUBLIC_SAFETY",
			"question": "What happens if you are carrying overload in goods carriages?",
			"options": [
				"It is not a punishable offence",
				"Only attracts a fine",
				"Driving licence can be suspended or cancelled"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},
		{
			"category": "ROAD_KNOWLEDGE",
			"question": "When you reach an intersection where there is no signal light or a traffic police man, you should:",
			"options": [
				"Give way to traffic approaching the intersection from other roads",
				"Give proper signal, sound the horn and then proceed",
				"Give way to the traffic approaching the intersection on your right side and proceed after giving necessary signals"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},
		{
			"category": "ROAD_KNOWLEDGE",
			"question": "When is overtaking prohibited?",
			"options": [
				"When the road is marked with a broken center line in the colour white",
				"When the vehicle is being driven on a steep hill",
				"When the road is marked with a continuous center line in the colour yellow"
			],
			"answer": 2
		},
		{
			"category": "ROAD_KNOWLEDGE",
			"question": "If the road is marked with broken white lines, you:",
			"options": [
				"Shall not change track",
				"Can change track, if required",
				"Shall stop the vehicle"
			],
			"answer": 2
		},
		{
			"category": "ROAD_KNOWLEDGE",
			"question": "Maximum permitted speed of a motor car on national highway is:",
			"options": ["60 km/hr", "70 km/hr", "80 km/hr"],
			"answer": 2
		},

		{
			"category": "BASIC_UNDERSTANDING",
			"question": "Before starting the engine of a vehicle, you should:",
			"options": [
				"Check radiator water level and engine oil level",
				"Check headlight",
				"Check the brakes"
			],
			"answer": 1
		},

		{
			"category": "BASIC_UNDERSTANDING",
			"question": "According to Section 113 of the Motor Vehicle Act 1988, a driver should not drive a vehicle:",
			"options": [
				"After consuming alcohol",
				"Exceeding the speed limit",
				"Exceeding the weight permitted to carry"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},

		{
			"category": "TRAFFIC_RULES",
			"question": "The middle lane is for:",
			"options": ["Overtaking", "Traffic driving at 40km/hr", "Two wheelers"],
			"answer": 2
		},
		{
			"category": "TRAFFIC_RULES",
			"question": "A flashing yellow signal is used when:",
			"options": [
				"Traffic lights are not working",
				"You should slow down and proceed with caution",
				"There is construction going on nearby"
			],
			"answer": 2
		},
		{
			"category": "TRAFFIC_RULES",
			"question": "Where, out of the following, are you allowed to park?",
			"options": [
				"A footpath",
				"On top of a hill",
				"Neither of the options above"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},
		{
			"category": "TRAFFIC_RULES",
			"question": "A high beam in foggy conditions:",
			"options": [
				"Is good because you can see more clearly",
				"Is bad because it reflects back and can dazzle",
				"Makes sure that others can see you"
			],
			"answer": 2
		},
		{
			"category": "TRAFFIC_RULES",
			"question": "When should you switch on your hazard warning lights?",
			"options": [
				"When you are moving straight",
				"When your vehicle is parked and the same is causing inconvenience to other road users",
				"When your vehicle parked in a no parking area"
			],
			"answer": 2
		},

		{
			"category": "BASIC_UNDERSTANDING",
			"question": "How can you distinguish a transport vehicle?",
			"options": [
				"By looking at the tyre size",
				"By the colour of the vehicle",
				"By looking at the number plate of the vehicle"
			],
			"answer": 3
		},

		{
			"category": "BASIC_UNDERSTANDING",
			"question": "Driver of a motor vehicle shall drive through:",
			"options": [
				"The right side of the road",
				"The left side of the road",
				"The centre of the road"
			],
			"answer": 2
		}
	]
}
